backroads.com 2019-03-19

# Backroads Privacy Policy

**Effective date: May 24, 2018**

Our relationship with you is very important to us. We are sensitive to protecting the private information that you provide to us. We also want you to have the opportunity to receive interesting and useful information about Backroads and about related products and services. 

This Privacy Policy sets out how we obtain, store and use your personal information when you use or interact with www.backroads.com or my.backroads.com (our web sites), or where we otherwise obtain or collect your personal information. By using any of our web sites or sharing your personal information with us, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. We recommend that you print a copy of this Privacy Policy and any future versions in force from time to time for your records.

The data controller in respect of our website is Backroads of 801 Cedar Street, Berkeley, CA, 94710, USA. You can contact the data controller by sending an email to [privacy@backroads.com](mailto:privacy@backroads.com).

**How we collect or obtain information about you**  
Each time a user visits our website, certain use and navigation information is collected by our servers. This information is aggregate and anonymous. It gives us information such as the number, frequency and duration of visits to each web page which we use to improve the content and navigation features of our website. A third-party cookie may also be placed on your computer which will collect information about your visit to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Usage of such cookies is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

If you would like to opt out of accepting cookies altogether, you can generally set your browser to not accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. However, certain features of our web sites or other services may not work optimally if you delete or disable cookies.

You can view Google’s uses of information here: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>

We collect personal information about you when you provide it to us, such as through your use of our website and its features, when you contact us directly by email, phone, in writing, or via social media, when you order goods and services, when you use any of our other websites or applications or any other means by which you provide personal information to us. The type of information we collect about you may include information such as:

  * Your name
  * Your email address
  * Your address
  * Your phone number
  * Your payment information (e.g. your credit or debit card details)
  * Information about your computer (e.g. your IP address and browser type)
  * Information about how you use our website (e.g. which pages you have viewed, the time you viewed them and what you clicked on)
  * Information about your mobile device (such as your geographical location)

Information we obtain from third parties will generally be your name and contact details, but may include any additional information they provide to us, including (but not limited to) any of the types of information set out in the list above.

We may also obtain personal information about you from certain publicly accessible sources, including (but not limited to) the electoral register, online customer databases, business directories, media publications, social media, websites and other publicly accessible sources.

Please note that there are circumstances in which we may not be required to provide you with the information contained in this Privacy Policy, for example if you already have the information.

In addition, where we obtain personal information about you from a source other than yourself, we are not required to provide you with certain information contained in this Privacy Policy if:

  * You already have the information
  * Providing you with the information would prove impossible or would involve a disproportionate effort
  * We are under an EU or EU member state law obligation to obtain or disclose the information which provides appropriate measures to protect your legitimate interests
  * We are obliged to keep the information confidential as a result of an obligation of professional secrecy regulated by EU or EU member state law

**Voluntary Surveys**  
We periodically survey our guests and catalog requesters for their vacation interests and related travel patterns. We encourage you to complete these surveys because: a) they provide us with information that helps us improve the types of trips we offer; and b) they help us direct specific Backroads messages to you that you may find most interesting. Your participation in these surveys is always voluntary.

**Name, Address, Contact, Survey and Billing Information**

We agree to: 

  * Honor guests' requests not to share their contact information with other marketers
  * Honor guests' requests not to receive mail, telephone or other solicitations from Backroads

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities, such as information processing, fulfilling guest orders, lead generation, providing pre/post and on-trip services, managing and enhancing guests data and conducting guest research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We may also combine the personal information you provide with other personal information available from other sources. This information will then be used to enhance and personalize your shopping experience, and to make our marketing efforts more efficient. Backroads does not sell your personal information to third parties.

Backroads ensures 3rd Party contracts contains proper controls for: anonymize and encryption of personal data, breach detection, and deletion of personal data at the end of contract term.

**MyBackroads Registration**  
If you register as a MyBackroads member, you may change any of the information provided when you register, except your Login ID and screen name, by logging into your account and editing your profile and options. You may request that your Login ID be changed by contacting us. You may not terminate your own membership, but it will be terminated upon your request. Click on the Contact link at the bottom of any Backroads web page for information on how to contact us.

**MyBackroads Email**  
Members of MyBackroads may not opt out of receiving service announcements and administrative messages. Members who do not wish to receive Backroads e-newsletters may opt out by following the instructions in the Backroads e-newsletter.

**MyBackroads Accounts**   
MyBackroads member accounts are secured by member-created passwords. Backroads takes precautions to ensure that member account information is kept private. We use reasonable measures to protect member information that is stored within our database, and we restrict access to member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff. Please note that we cannot guarantee the security of member account information. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of member information at any time.

**Access to Information**  
You have the right to request access to the information we have on you. You can do this by contacting us at [privacy@backroads.com](mailto:privacy@backroads.com). We will make sure to provide you with a copy of the data we process about you. In order to comply with your request, we may ask you to verify your identity. We will fulfill your request by sending your copy electronically, unless the request expressly specifies a different method.

**Sharing and Disclosure of Information Backroads Collects**  
Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, Backroads will not disclose personal information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: 

  * To conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other legal process received by Backroads, whether or not a response is required by applicable law
  * To enforce the Backroads Terms of Service Agreement or to protect our rights
  * To protect the safety of members of the public and users of the service.

Backroads reserves the right to transfer personal information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of Backroads or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest. For more information see the "Changes in Our Privacy Policy" section below.

**Information Correction and Deletion**  
If you believe that the information we have about you is incorrect, you can contact us to update it. Click on the Contact link at the bottom of any Backroads web page for information on how to contact us.

If at any point you wish for Backroads to delete information about you, please submit your request to [privacy@backroads.com](mailto:privacy@backroads.com).

**International Privacy Laws**  
If you are visiting our websites from outside the United States, please be aware that you are sending information (including personal data) to the United States where our servers are located. That information may then be transferred within the United States or back out of the United States to other countries outside of your country of residence, depending on the type of information and how it is stored by us. These countries (including the United States) may not necessarily have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in your country of residence; however, our collection, storage and use of your personal data will at all times be governed by this Privacy Policy.

**Opting Out of Marketing**  
The personally identifiable information that you provide to us and information about your order may be combined with other personally identifiable information from our records and other sources. This information will be used to make our future marketing efforts more efficient. We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to receive direct marketing from us, please let us know. Click on the Contact link at the bottom of any Backroads web page for information on how to contact us.

**Changes in Our Privacy Policy**  
We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will be available at www.backroads.com/privacy. If we make a change to this policy by continuing to access or use this site after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

**If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, pleasecontact us.**
